

PROFILE

Highly-skilled and motivated senior software engineer with more than 5 years of experience. Enhanced performance of 16 web and desktop applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC and Core. Increased revenue by analyzing and improving app monetization strategies. Seeking to draw on proven software development and engineering skills to increase and impressive line of Systems.

CONTACT

PHONE: +249999676284

EMAIL: ahmedkhojaly85@gmail.com GITHUB: https://github.com/saidak16

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/ahmed-khojaly-5b5867179

PERSONAL

Birth date: 1st Feb 1996 Nationality: Sudanese.

Address: Khartoum North, Sudan. Languages: Arabic (Native), English

SKILLS & STRENGTHS

- Net Developer (Full stack, Desktop Application).
- Excellent knowledge of the programing language: VB, C#, ASP.NET MVC/Web Forms/Core.
- Good knowledge of the programing language: Angular, Java, SQL.
- Good knowledge of Angular framework.
- Good Knowledge of ASP.NET Identity framework.
- Good Knowledge of DevOps Methodology.

Ahmed Khojaly Ahmed Ali

Senior Software Developer

EDUCATION

National Ribat University-Sudan

Oct 2013 - Aug 2017

Bachelor of Computer Science (First Class Honors).

CERTIFICATES:

- ➤ Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate [1Z0-1085-21]:
 - ✓ Credential ID: **OC2715997** | **Issued Jun 2022** · No Expiration Date

COURCES:

- Agile Methodology Scrum Framework Udemy.
- Application Lifecycle Development (DevOps) Udemy.
- Professional Skills.
- Full Stack Web and Mobile Development PLURALSIGHT.
- ASP.NET MVC/Core PLURALSIGHT.
- The Ultimate Design Patterns PLURALSIGHT.
- Business Analysis.

WORKSHOPS:

- Software Testing Fundamentals.
- Introduction to Agile Management.
- Getting Started with AWS Modern Applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CTC Group CO. LTD – Sudan (Senior Software Developer)

3^{ed} April 2022 – Currently: (https://ctcgroupltd.com)

- Develop, implement, and modify the company software applications to ensure operability, capacity and reliability to meet the current and future demands of the business.
- Provide support for successful implementation through rigorous troubleshooting and modification to develop more user friendly software.

Intelligent Analytics Company for Software Solutions – Sudan

(Project Based - Senior Software Developer)

16th July 2020 – 1st April 2022: (https://intlytics.com)

- Researching, designing, implementing, and managing software programs
- Testing and evaluating new programs
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications
- Writing and implementing efficient code.
- Developing quality assurance procedures

- Familiar with SAP Crystal Reports.
- Web services: REST, SOAP
- Good knowledge of: SOLID Principles.
- Database: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server and Oracle.
- Great understanding on coding standard and rules
- Understanding Trends & Roles in a Commercial Environment.
- Organizational & Time Management Skills
- Sharp problem solver.
- Accuracy & Attention to Detail.
- Creative thinking and Goals orientation.
- Teamwork and collaborate well with others.
- Compile timely, comprehensive and accurate documentation and or reports as requested.
- Possess up-to-date knowledge of technological developments in the industry.
- Communicate effectively and professionally in all forms of communication with team members.
- Possess strong problem solving and decision-making skills while using good judgment.
- Good Analytical and Business experience.
- Multi-task and change from onetask to another without loss of efficiency or composure.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- Good Project management skills.
- Good Understand for SOLID Principals.

Hash Information Technology – Sudan: (http://hash-sd.com) during my work duration, I held the following positions in the company:

- Product Manager (October 2021 March 2022):
 - **Outies and Responsibilities:**
 - Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business challenges.
 - Oversee and manage the software development lifecycle
 - Collaborate with the product owner to develop a product vision for the new product
 - Figure out the strengths and weaknesses of the competitors and use them to make a great product
 - Work on the prioritization of new features based on usability, functionality, and user experience.
- Senior Software Engineer (March 2020 September 2021):
 - Duties and Responsibilities:
 - Develop, test and implement new software programs
 - Design and update software database. This includes, but is not limited to: Software Applications, Web Sites, Data Communication Processes and User Interfaces
 - Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization
 - Independently install, customize and integrate commercial software packages
 - Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues
 - Work with team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing
 - Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability
 - Resolve complex technical design issues
 - Development of technical specifications and plans
 - Analyze user requirements and convert requirements to design documents

Multi Software Company Ltd. (M.S.C) – Sudan

(Project Based - Senior Software Developer)

25th August 2020 – 29th January 2021: (http://www.themsc.net)

- Researching, designing, implementing, and managing software programs
- Testing and evaluating new programs
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications
- Writing and implementing efficient code
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.

GPITCO CO. LTD – KSA (Project Based - Senior Software Developer)

31st May 2021 – 10st Nov 2021: (http://www.gpitco.com)

- Writing and implementing efficient code
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts
- Enhancing applications by identifying opportunities for improvement, making recommendations and designing and implementing systems.
- Design and update software database. This includes, but is not limited to:Software Applications, Web Sites, Data Communication Processes and User Interfaces.

PROJECTS:

- Development of Cars Rental Web-App System as part of development team (ASP.NET MVC).
- Attendance and Departure Management System (C#).
- Sales Management System (C#).
- Movies Rental Web-App (ASP.NET MVC).
- Jobs Offers Web-App (ASP.NET MVC).
- Development of Unity Gym v4.3
 System as part of development team
 (C#).
- **Gig Hub** Web-App (ASP.NET MVC).
- Version Control System

 Hash Tech. (ASP.NET

 Web Forms).
- **Product Marketing** Web-Site (ASP.NET MVC).
- Courses Management Web-App (ASP.NET MVC).
- Development of EDU PRO V2.0.0 as part of development team (ASP.NET Web Forms).
- Registration System for the Activities of Al Ibdaa Association (ASP.NET Web Forms).
- Development of **Power Gym** mobileApp as part of development team (RESTful API).
- **Restaurants POS** Web-App (ASP.NET MVC).
- Inventory Management System (APOODS Co.) Desktop App (C#).
- Book Store Management System Web-App (ASP.NET Core)
- Development of EDU.PRO E-Payment API for Faisal Islamic Bank - Sudan (Core API).
- Development of EDU.PRO E-Payment API for Omdurman National Bank - Sudan (Core API).
- Development of DigiTech App APIfor CTC Group - Sudan (Core API).
- Development of E-Certificate for Sudanese medical specialization board (Web Core).
- Development of LIPER App for LIPER Company- Sudan (Core API).
- Development of Pharmacy
 Management System (POS) for AL NOOR Pharmacy- Sudan (Windows Forms).

FINITYLOOPS CO. LTD – Sudan (Software Developer)

25th Feb 2019 – 7th March 2020: (http://finityloops.com)

- Develop, test and implement new software programs.
- Design and update software database. This includes, but is not limited to:Software Applications, Web Sites, Data Communication Processes and User Interfaces.
- Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization.
- Independently install, customize and integrate commercial softwarepackages.
- Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues.
- Work with team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, reviewnew and existing code and/or perform unit testing.
- Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability.
- Development of technical specifications and plans. Resolve complex technical design issues.
- Analyze user requirements and convert requirements to design documents.
- Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business challenges.

National Audit Chamber – (Internship – Technical Support)

25th Mar 2018 – 21st Feb 2019: (http://audit.gov.sd)

- Training on the computerized system of accounts and personnel affairs (ERP).
- Participate in Oracle reports Designing and Coding.
- Support and optimize Desktop peripherals, Printer, projectors and other ICT devices
- Support on File sharing Management.
- Basic Network and Connectivity Maintenance.
- Setting Desktop and laptops include OS installation, antivirus.
- Monthly Check on PCs and Laptops and IT Infrastructure.
- Supplies Employees with IT equipment.
- On call Support for IT related Problems.

African Exchange Company LTD – (Internship - Technical Support)

10th Oct 2016 - 27th Oct 2016:

- Follow-up of the management of the office and supervisor of the branch in reviewing the attendance, departure and daily movement of individuals.
- Help the PR department provide the company's requirements.
- Assisting the Personal Affairs Department in arranging files and reviewing the conditions and regulations of the labor office regarding the discipline and behavior of employees.
- Training in the Department of Foreign Remittances, both received and issued through a direct accounting program with correspondents.

References:

- Mr. Gassim Muddather Mohamed.
 - ✓ Director of IT Department, National Audit Chamber Sudan.
 - ✓ Tel.: +249912971617.
 - ✓ Work Email: eng.gassim@audit.gov.sd
 - ✓ Personal Email: <u>Gsoom_4@hotmail.com</u>

• Eng. Ahmed Essam

- ✓ Deputy Director of IT Department, National Audit Chamber
 Sudan.
- ✓ Tel.: +249 96 129 1249
- ✓ Work Email: ahmed.essam@audit.gov.sd
- ✓ Personal Email: gahtoni2018@hotmail.com

• Eng. Atif Haroon Saleh Guma

- ✓ Information Management Officer, **Danish Refugee Council.**
- ✓ Tel.: +2499111760700
- ✓ Work Email: atif.guma@drc.ngo
- ✓ Personal Email: <u>atifharoon12@yahoo.com</u>

• Eng. Mohamed Modawi Almahi Ali

- ✓ Senior cloud & Infrastructure Engineer, Syber Technology Co. - Sudan
- ✓ Tel.: +249 92 652 9404
- ✓ Work Email: Mohamed.m@sybertechnology.com
- ✓ Personal Email: Mohamed.modawi94@gmail.com